<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>steven liao</title>
    <link>https://stevenliao.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on steven liao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 14:10:11 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenliao.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>valuing nfl draft picks</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/draft_pick_valuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 14:10:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/draft_pick_valuation/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: We make a model valuing draft picks according to how much they outperform their rookie contract (using historical data from 1994-2016). Draft picks tend to be underpaid on the whole (as expected), serving as cheap talent (whereas free agents are &amp;lsquo;properly priced talent&amp;rsquo;). The most underpaid draft picks are in the late first round and early second round; counterintuitively, this suggests they could actually be worth more than high first round picks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>credits</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/credits/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 12:17:02 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/credits/</guid>
      <description>font My preferred font (and my favorite font in general) for viewing this site: Brown by Aurele Sacks.
But, you probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need me to tell you that, if you&amp;rsquo;re seeing it ;).
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have Brown installed on your machine (and you probably don&amp;rsquo;t if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure) you&amp;rsquo;re probably viewing this site through Open Sans and Didact Gothic.
artwork Thanks to the talented Jennifer Zhu for commissioning my self-portraits!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 10:49:56 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey there - I&amp;rsquo;m Steven - thanks for visiting my site :).
This site is for me to post my random musings and projects related to sports analytics. It&amp;rsquo;s not intended to be overly academic or technical, content-restrained, nor will I plan to do any heavy editoralizing. I like to think of the content as glorified reddit posts, where I strive to follow a particular nugget of advice from Youtubers everywhere, &amp;lsquo;Create Content you would like to see&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>