<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on steven liao</title>
    <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on steven liao</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:35:27 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://stevenliao.me/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>nfl positional value: cap spending by position from 2003 to 2017</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/nfl_positional_value/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 14:35:27 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/nfl_positional_value/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Teams are devoting more spending resources to &amp;lsquo;passing players&amp;rsquo; - players who feature in the passing game (quarterback, wide receiver), and players who defend the passing game (defensive backs).
We&amp;rsquo;ve all heard the story that the NFL is becoming a passing league. And most would agree that running backs in particular, have seen their value go down in recent years.
One way to measure positional value is to measure how much of its cap space a team is willing to devote to each position - aka how much &amp;lsquo;cap market share&amp;rsquo; a position takes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nba: how does the rise of the 3-pointer impact offensive rebounding strategy?</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/offensive_rebounding_strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Aug 2018 16:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/offensive_rebounding_strategy/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: Teams that play &amp;ldquo;Morey-Ball&amp;rdquo; should value offensive rebounds more, and consider devoting more resources to grabbing them.
Rebounding is fairly valuable in basketball, as a rebound results in additional possession (worth over 1 point). With points per possession increasing league-wide as a result of the NBA&amp;rsquo;s recent 3-point revolution, why, in fact, are offensive rebounding numbers dropping to all-time lows?
In this post we are concerned with the following strategic questions:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a better way to measure game closeness</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/integrated_point_differential/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 15:04:03 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/integrated_point_differential/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: The final score does not tell the whole story regarding how close a game was. Integrated Point Differential (IPD) improves upon Point Differential by accounting for the score throughout the game, as opposed to just the final score. Spread Integrated Point Differential (SIPD) adjusts IPD with respect to the spread, and could be a useful proxy for whether a bet was the right side (even if it didn&amp;rsquo;t cover).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>basics of sports betting</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/basic_intro_betting/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 14:48:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/basic_intro_betting/</guid>
      <description>In my content, I may frequently reference sports betting terminology / ideas. Under the dry not wet principle, I am writing this guide.
If a sportsbook is a restaurant, betting lines are the menu items you can choose from. Betting lines tell you who (which team or individual) you&amp;rsquo;re betting on, conditions for winning the bet, and how much money you&amp;rsquo;ll receive if you win. Just as with restaurants, the menu of betting lines differs by sportsbook; some offer better odds, some offer more diverse menu items (WNBA, high school football), some even offer build-your-own bets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>valuing nfl draft picks</title>
      <link>https://stevenliao.me/post/draft_pick_valuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 14:10:11 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stevenliao.me/post/draft_pick_valuation/</guid>
      <description>TLDR: We make a model valuing draft picks according to how much they outperform their rookie contract (using historical data from 1994-2016). Draft picks tend to be underpaid on the whole (as expected), serving as cheap talent (whereas free agents are &amp;lsquo;properly priced talent&amp;rsquo;). The most underpaid draft picks are in the late first round and early second round; counterintuitively, this suggests they could actually be worth more than high first round picks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>